翻译：草草  CS漫画家小明  鱼小姐  潇湘月影  Reginamoon  香茗小焙
翻译：木浅薰  某羽  小饭   校对：某羽
时间轴：包包  kallen  小式
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第四季   第十六集
季终
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on Suits
-杰夫  -杰西卡  你说的对
- Jeff... - Jessica, you were right.
要么两者兼得  要么两者皆失
We either need to have both, or it's not going to work.
此刻起  我提出辞职
Effective immediately, I'm tendering my resignation.
傅滋曼可不会做没有回报
Forstman doesn't throw money around
白白撒钱的亏本生意
without getting something in return.
他会赚到钱
He's gonna get money in return.
他的心中钱只排在第三位
Money is third on his list.
前两位是报复人
The first two are getting back at people
和控制人
and getting control of people.
你这个混蛋
Son of a bitch.
你让我来不是为了让你签字
You didn't bring me here for you to sign on the arrows.
而是为了让我签字
You brought me here for me to sign on the arrows.
没错
Yep.
伍德尔失去工作后
After Woodall lost his job,
傅滋曼把他安排到了证监会
Forstman got him installed at the S.E.C.,
证据在哪里
Where's the proof?
在埃里克·伍德尔的银行账户里
In Eric Woodall's bank accounts.
太可笑了
This is ridiculous.
我是你上司
I'm your boss.
先生们  给我一分钟
Gentlemen, give me a minute.
你就是逼我
You're forcing me to turn you in
检举你12年前做的事情
for what you did 12 years ago.
你不会的
You're not gonna do that,
因为你也牵涉其中了  伙计
because you did it too, pal.
其他人对我失去信心
Anyone else every loses faith in me,
我根本不在乎
it doesn't matter.
但你不行
But with you, it's different.
我该走了
I should go.
为什么
Why?
你知道我爱你  唐娜
You know I love you, Donna.
敬哈维
To Harvey.
敬哈维  干杯
To Harvey. Cheers.
杰伊  给我杯麦卡伦18年
Jay, can I get a Macallan 18?
要知道  一般来说第一次胜诉
You know, usually when someone wins their first trial,
至少会假装把助理地检官同事们
they at least pretend to finish the drink
买的酒喝完
their fellow ADAs bought them.
抱歉  我们...
I'm sorry, do we--
认识吗  还不呢
Know each other? Not yet.
但今天你走运
But today's your lucky day.
为什么
And why is that?
因为你今天能结识唐娜
Because it's the day you get to meet Donna.
我猜猜  你就是唐娜
And let me guess. You're Donna.
你可不知道我有多唐娜
Oh, you have no idea how Donna I am.
-好吧  唐娜  我是哈维...  -斯佩克特
- Well, Donna, I'm Harvey-- - Harvey Specter.
你觉得我要是不知道你是谁
You really think I'd be talking to you
还会跟你说话吗
if I didn't know who you were?
那你究竟怎么知道我的
And how exactly do you know about me?
我知道所有人
I know about everybody.
我不知道的是
What I don't know is
为什么选这个案子作为你的法庭处子秀
why this is the first case you ever took to trial.
因为是白领犯罪
Because it was a white-collar crime,
不是街角的毒贩
not some drug dealer on a corner,
所以这种案子
which makes it the kind of case--
能让你上报纸
That puts your name in the paper.
你不仅是长得美  是吧
You're not just a pretty face, are you?
的确
No, I'm not.
所以或许你该请我一杯酒
So maybe you should buy me a drink,
我们可以去角落里继续对话
and we can continue this conversation in the corner.
杰伊
Jay?
肖恩  你大晚上的
Sean, what are you doing in my building
跑来我公寓楼做什么
in the middle of the night?
我以为你不跟踪我了
I thought we were done with you following me.
我没跟踪你
I'm not following you.
我在等你
I'm waiting for you.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
你需要  还是证监会
You need my help, or the SEC needs my help?
都需要
We both do.
但现在  我更在乎我自己
But at the moment, I care more about me
而不是证监会
than I do about the SEC.
我找不到那笔钱了
I can't find the money.
什么意思
What do you mean you can't find the money?
你这三个月都在做什么
What the hell have you been doing for the last three months?
找钱
Looking for the money.
那就再使劲点找
Then look harder,
伍德尔可不是做慈善的
because Woodall isn't in the charity business.
傅兹曼贿赂人
Forstman buys people,
我们把那人双手奉上了
and we handed them to you on a silver platter.
我为你冒了险
And I stuck my neck out for you,
指控我朋友受贿
and I accused my friend of being on the take.
如果我不能把事做到底
Now, if I can't follow through with that,
埃里克·伍德尔就要逃脱罪责了
Eric Woodall walks.
查尔斯·傅兹曼也是
Charles Forstman walks.
你凭什么觉得  你都找不到那笔钱
Well, what makes you think I can find the money
我却能找到呢
when you couldn't?
我不知道你能不能
I don't know if you can or not,
但这个案子我只剩五天时间了
but they're gonna shut me down in five days,
能获得的帮助我都需要
and I need all the help I can get.
不说我了  说说你吧
Okay, enough about me. Let's talk about you.
这是我最喜欢的话题
Ooh, my favorite subject.
你知道我怎么想吗
You know what I think?
我觉得你最喜欢的话题找上我
I think your favorite subject didn't come up to me
不是为了弄清楚我为什么上庭
just to find out why I went to trial.
你有所求
You want something.
是啊
I sure do.
我觉得我或许能给你
And I think I might be ready to give it to you.
不是性
It's not sex.
那当我没说
Then never mind.
你还真是坦诚啊
Wow, you're gonna be that honest about it.
省时间嘛
Saves time.
那我也不绕弯  我要做你的秘书
Well, in that case, I want to move to your desk.
为什么
And why is that?
因为人人知道  你再过几年
Because it's no secret that in a few years,
就要回高登·施密特·范·戴克律所
you're going back to Gordon, Schmidt, and Van Dyke.
我猜猜  你到时想一起来
And let me guess, you want to come with me when I do.
不
No, I don't.
那为什么
Then why?
因为我要做个演员
Because I'm gonna be an actress,
我想要一个知道
and I want somebody who understands
人生不止局限于地检官办公室的人
that there's more to life than just the DA's office.
而且我能付出一切
And that I can give my all to them
但偶尔还能去试镜
but still step out for the occasional audition.
你这就要抛弃我啊
So you're stepping out on me already?
是的  但重点是
Yes, but the important thing is,
我提前告诉你了啊
I'm telling you about it in advance.
麦卡伦36年
Macallan 36.
我没点这个啊
I didn't order a Macallan 36.
那边的先生送的
It's from the gentleman over there.
我不知道那人是谁
Okay, I don't know who that is,
但我现在就告诉你  他是麻烦
but I'm telling you right now, he is bad news.
你看上去很不一样
You look different.
我就当是夸我了
I will take that as a compliment.
我是说我没想到会见到你这样子...
I meant I wasn't expecting to see you like that--
我知道你什么意思
I-I know what you meant.
你的意思是  你根本没想到
What you really meant is that you weren't expecting
会看到我
to see me at all.
什么
Excuse me?
拜托  哈维
Come on, Harvey.
自从迈克回到律所
Ever since Mike came back to the firm,
你就一直视我不存在
I've basically been nonexistent to you.
怎么了
What's going on?
卡荷尔找不到那笔钱
Cahill can't find the money.
什么叫找不到那笔钱
What do you mean he can't find the money?
他这么长时间都在做什么啊
What's he been doing this whole time?
-我也这么问的  -那他怎么说
- Yeah, that's what I said. - And what did he say?
他说他遇到麻烦了  需要我们帮忙
He said he's in trouble and he needs our help.
我要告诉你一些不能告诉他的事
And I'm gonna tell you what I couldn't tell him.
他找不到钱
He can't find the money
是因为他找错了地方
because he's been looking in the wrong place.
那应该去哪里找
So where's the right place?
我也不太清楚
I don't know exactly.
但就在某处存在着一个埃里克·伍德尔在乎的人
But somewhere, there's a person Eric Woodall cares about,
那里就是钱的去处
and that's where the money went.
我们为什么不能跟卡荷尔这么说
And why can't we tell Cahill that?
因为我不想让他知道我是如何知道这件事的
Because I don't want him to know how I know it.
-那你是怎么知道的  -我就是知道
- How do you know it? - Because I know.
你想要个存在的机会
You want a chance to exist?
那就想出方法解决这件事
Figure out a way to get this done.
我需要你  路易
路易  我收到你的便条了
Louis, I got your note,
我也知道诺玛还没回来
and I know that Norma's still out,
但我真的没时间...
but I really don't have time to--
诺玛死了
Norma's dead.
什么
What?
她今早照顾她姐姐时去世了
She died this morning taking care of her sister.
路易  我很遗憾
Oh, Louis, I'm so sorry.
不用装了  唐娜
You don't need to fake it, Donna.
我没有在装
I'm not faking it.
她是个不错的人
She was a sweet woman.
她就是个母老虎
She was a frickin' battle-ax is what she was.
过去的每一天
There wasn't a day that went by
我都想把她曲张的静脉拽出来
that I didn't want to rip out
然后用它来勒死她
one of her varicose veins and strangle her with it.
好吧  我觉得你现在
Okay, I don't think you're in touch with
无法认清自己的真实想法
how you're really feeling right now.
我现在的感觉就是她一如既往地
How I'm feeling is that she left me high and dry
留我在这里孤立无援
just like she always did.
你还想让她继续工作
You expect her to keep working?
看看这个
Look at this.
这是她全部的财产清单
It's her entire estate laid out on paper.
她没办法管理好我的日程
She couldn't manage my calendar,
自己的生活倒管得细致入微
but this crap that she plans within an inch of her life.
你希望我确保这些
And you want me to make sure
资产得到妥善安置吗
these things are bequeathed properly?
你把它们全拿去填充玩具我也没意见
You can stuff them in a giant pinata for all I care.
我还得去找个像样的罐子
I have to go find the perfect urn
装着她的骨灰从楼顶扔下去
to throw her ashes off the top of the building.
她这么要求的
She requested that?
没有  她想把骨灰放在我这里
No, she wanted them to be in here with me,
但我绝不会那么做的
but like hell I'm gonna do that.
好吧  路易  我帮你处理这件事
Okay, Louis, I will take care of this for you,
但你不能在我不在的时候去撒她的骨灰
but you're not throwing her ashes anywhere without me.
好吧
Okay, fine.
那你需要我去和哈维打个招呼吗
Do you want me to smooth things over with Harvey for you?
不用
No.
哈维现在自己靠自己就很好
Harvey will be just fine on his own.
我知道你是谁  我不感兴趣
I know who you are, and I'm not interested.
就因为我的名声不好吗
Just 'cause I got a bad reputation?
是我不想因为把你的对手关起来了
Because I'm not accepting a drink
就和你喝酒
for putting your rival behind bars.
你想错了  伙计
You got the wrong idea, pal.
我请你喝酒不是因为你把我的敌人关起来了
I didn't buy you that for putting my enemy away.
而是因为你把他关进去的方法
I bought you that for how you put my enemy away.
好吧  你得到我的注意了
Okay, you got me.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你
You.
你身上有些特别的东西
You've got something special.
我希望这样的人
And I want people with something special
为我工作
working for me.
我为什么会想要为你工作
Why exactly would I want to work for you?
我可以想到一百万个理由
I can think of a million reasons,
那正是我要给你的签约奖金
'cause that's the signing bonus I'm gonna give you,
那个数额也远超过
and that's a hell of a lot more money
你做一辈子律师能挣到的钱
than you're ever gonna make as a lawyer.
那我如果告诉你
And what if I told you
我当律师不是为了钱呢
I don't practice law to make money?
那我就会问你  你当律师是为了什么
Then I'd ask you, what do you practice it for?
为了让人们按我的意愿行事
To bend people to my will.
那就为我让别人按你的意愿行事
Then bend people to your will for me
除此之外再大赚一笔
and make a lot of money on top of it.
但傅滋曼先生  事情是这样的
Well, here's the thing, Mr. Forstman.
虽然这跟你没什么关系
Not that it's any of your business,
但我马上就可以每年挣五十万
but I'll be making 1/2 million a year in no time.
每年挣五十万算个屁
1/2 million a year is dick.
我的园丁都挣那么多
My gardener makes that.
那就把这工作给你园丁把
Then go offer your gardener a job,
因为我不感兴趣
because I'm not interested.
顺便说一句
Just so you know,
如果你改变主意想来找我了
if you change your mind and come back to me,
那时候情况可就不一样了
it's not gonna be the same conversation.
谢谢你的酒  祝你好运  傅滋曼先生
Thanks for the drink. Good luck, Mr. Forstman.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你觉得我在干什么
What do you think I'm doing?
如果傅滋曼把钱给了伍德尔亲近的人
If Forstman gave the money to someone Woodall's close to,
我们需要开始画家谱了
we need to start by compiling a family tree.
我是说你今天怎么不去上学
I meant why aren't you at school today?
因为我要向哈维证明我确实存在
Because I'm gonna prove to Harvey that I exist.
好吧
Okay.
既然你提起了  昨晚是怎么回事
Now that you mention it, what was that last night?
自从你回来
Ever since you came back,
就好像你和哈维在说着某种秘密语言
it's like you and Harvey speak this secret language,
而我却参与不进去
and I'm not a part of it.
瑞秋  别这样  我们有感情基础的
Rachel, come on. We have history.
我说的不是感情基础  我说的是尊重
I'm not talking about history. I'm talking about respect.
好吧  如果你认为哈维不尊重你
Okay, you don't know what you're talking about
那你一定是想错了
if you think Harvey doesn't respect you.
你是想跟我说昨晚
Are you gonna tell me that last night
他没有给你个表情暗示
he didn't give you a look that said,
"你不用全告诉她
"You don't need to tell her the full story
因为她没必要知道"
because she doesn't need to know"?
瑞秋  他用眼神示意
Rachel, he didn't give me that look
不是因为他不尊重你
because he doesn't respect you.
而是因为他觉得羞耻
He gave me that look because he's ashamed.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
这么说吧  被查尔斯·傅滋曼耍过的
Let's just say that I'm not the only one
并不是只有我一个
that Charles Forstman duped.
-哈维也被傅滋曼摆过一道  -是的
- Harvey got taken by Forstman? - Yes.
他只告诉了我  因为他不得不说
And he only told me because he had to
那时收购战激战正酣
when we were in the middle of that takeover battle.
所以哈维才谁都不在乎
That's why Harvey's so slow to care about anybody.
傅滋曼利用了他在意的人
Forstman used somebody he cared about.
该死  我怎么没想到过
Holy shit. I never even thought about that.
你觉得会是谁
Who do you think it was?
我不知道  但我有个不错的猜想
I don't know, but I have a pretty good guess.
你觉得怎么样
Well, what do you think?
我觉得这地方很逊  而我很忙
I think this place is a dump, and I'm busy,
所以为什么不直说  叫我来干什么
so why don't you tell me why we're here?
我想在这开餐厅
I want to open a restaurant here.
马库斯  这里已经是一家餐厅了
Marcus, there's already a restaurant here.
而且买卖不好
And it isn't working.
所以他们租不下去了
Which is why they're gonna lose their lease.
看看这个
Take a look.
我已经找到了厨师
I've got a chef.
取得了酒类许可证
I've got a liquor license.
还有改造计划
I've got renovation plans.
我万事俱备
I have everything I need.
只差资金
Except the money.
我需要十五万美元
I need $150,000.
-你疯了  -拜托  哈维
- Are you crazy? - Come on, Harvey.
这是我的梦想
This is my dream.
我知道我能干好
I know I can make this work.
我不是说你不能
And I'm not saying you can't,
但我没有这笔钱
but I don't have that kind of money.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
你是大牌律师
You're the big-time lawyer
而且刚刚上了报纸
who just got his name in the paper.
上了报纸  也没人多给我钱
My name in the paper doesn't pay me extra money.
我每年收入是五万美元
I make $50,000 a year.
你说过你要当企业律师了
And you said you were gonna be a corporate lawyer.
是的  我当了之后可以帮助你  但现在...
Yeah, and when I am, I can help you, but right now...
我才不管你现在怎样
I don't give a shit about right now.
我只在乎你什么时候才能
I give a shit about when you were supposed to be
有个大哥的样子  可你呢  做了什么
my big brother, but instead, what did you do?
我知道我做了什么
I know what I did.
那你知道  我这辈子
Then you know I can never get a loan
都贷不到款吧
for as long as I live.
马库斯  你什么时候才能对自己
Marcus, when are you gonna take responsibility
负起责任呢
for your own shit?
你以为我这是在干什么
What the hell does it look like I'm trying to do?
我第一个来找你  是因为我知道你希望我成功
I came to you first because I know you'd want me to,
但如果你不想帮我
but if you don't come through,
我就去找妈妈
I'm gonna go to Mom.
你不是想找妈妈
You don't mean Mom.
是想找他
You mean him.
你一份钱也不许跟那个男人要
And you're not taking a nickel from that man.
拿他的钱  也不会
Taking his money isn't gonna make
让他对爸爸做出的事变得更糟
what he did to Dad any worse.
这是胡扯  你心知肚明
That's bullshit, and you know it,
我不会让你这么干的
and I'm not gonna let you do it.
哈维
Hey, Harvey.
你要怎么阻止我
How the hell are you gonna stop me?
是我疯了吗
Am I crazy,
还是你确实穿了
or is that the same dress you were wearing
上次见你时那条裙子
the last time I saw you?
肯定是你疯了
You must be crazy,
因为我从不穿同一件衣服
because I don't wear the same dress ever.
那你的衣橱肯定投入了巨资
Then you must spend a fortune on wardrobe.
但我必须说  这很值得
But I have to say, it's worth it.
我突然觉得  你不是顺路来拜访那么简单
I suddenly get the feeling this isn't just a drop-by.
我想加快速度
I want to move up our timeline.
哈维  我们说好的
Harvey, we have a deal.
我给你做担保
I put myself on the line for you,
而这个约定不能改
and our deal is not going to change.
我可以把钱还你  自己另谋高就
I could just pay you the money back and move on.
如果你能那么做  你就不会到这来
And if you could do that, you wouldn't be here
要求回来
asking to come back.
这次马库斯又输了多少钱
How much money did Marcus lose this time?
他没输钱  他想开一家餐厅
He didn't lose anything. He wants to start a restaurant.
他什么都不想开
He doesn't want to start shit.
他是又欠债了
He owes somebody something.
你不了解情况  他已经浪子回头了
You don't know that. He's turned his life around.
在我看来  他有问题
What I know is, he has a problem,
而且他想从你这里拿钱
and he's looking to get money from you.
而你不会从我这里拿到钱的
And you're not gonna get it from me.
那我就从别的地方弄
Then I'll get it somewhere else.
这话什么意思
And what's that supposed to mean?
查尔斯·傅滋曼要我去为他工作
I got a job offer from Charles Forstman.
看着我
Look at me.
我不管他向你许诺了什么
I don't care what he's offering you.
不要接受
Don't take it.
是因为他名声很差吗
Because he's got a bad reputation?
你以为我不知道吗
You think I don't know that?
我觉得你自以为知道很多事
I think there are a lot of things
但其实你并不了解
you think you know that you don't.
我只知道  要么你帮助我
What I know is, you're either gonna help me
要么查尔斯·傅滋曼帮我
or Charles Forstman is.
都取决于你
It's up to you.
哈维  我无法强迫你听我的
Harvey, I can't make you listen to me,
但我不会让你到这来
but what I'm not going to do is let you come here
用一个卑鄙的银行家
and leverage me with some bullshit offer
来威胁我给你些什么  所以随你便
from a shady banker, so do what you're gonna do.
别说我没有警告过你
But don't say I didn't warn you.
你要买多少"奇迹面包"都行  埃里克
You can buy all the Wonder Bread you want, Eric,
但你没法带进监狱
but you can't take it with you to prison.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我来提醒你一旦他们找到那笔钱
I'm here to remind you that once they find the money,
事情就全败露了
it's all gonna come tumbling down.
他们找不到的
Well, they're not gonna find the money,
因为根本没有那笔钱
'cause there is no money.
不在你的账户  卡荷尔不知道但我知道
Not in your accounts, but I know what Cahill doesn't.
傅滋曼把钱交给你在乎的人
Forstman gave it to somebody you care about,
等我告诉他  那一切就太晚了
and if I tell him that, it'll be too late.
我知道你想干什么
I know what you're trying to do.
你想引我把钱转走
You're trying to bait me into moving the body.
我们都知道你没那么傻
We both know you're not dumb enough to do that.
我是来给跟你做个交易
I'm here to get you to cut a deal
让你供出傅滋曼
and turn Forstman in.
你没资格跟我谈交易
You don't have the authority to cut a deal.
确实  但你雇我当你律师后
No, but I can get Cahill to
我可以让卡荷尔来谈交易
after you hire me to represent you.
你说雇只狐狸来看鸡舍
You mean hire the fox to watch the henhouse?
门都没有
Not a chance.
埃里克  他们就要查到你了
Eric, they're closing in,
一旦查到  你就需要找我了
and when they do, you're gonna want to call me.
不如你先收下我的名片
So why don't you take my card?
太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
伍德尔找到30个值得怀疑的人
Woodall's got 30 people it could be,
但也可能根本不在这30人里
or it could be none of them.
我知道  但这是我们的任务
I know that, but this is our job.
不  我们的任务是帮哈维打败傅滋曼
No, our job is to help Harvey get Forstman.
如果你确实在想我觉得你在想的事
If you're thinking what I think you're thinking--
-是的  -瑞秋  我们不可能让哈维
- I am, and you are too. - Rachel, we are never gonna get Harvey
去为12年前的事对付傅滋曼
to go after Forstman for what they did 12 years ago.
为什么  因为他弟弟吗
Why, because of his brother?
对  因为他弟弟  也可能因为他惭愧
Yes, because of his brother, or because he's ashamed.
不管怎么说  他知道有种可能性
Either way, he knows it's a possibility.
他用不着我去告诉他
He doesn't need me to tell him about it.
不  他只是不需要我去告诉他
No, he just doesn't need me to tell him about it.
-瑞秋  -跟我存不存在无关
- Rachel-- - This is not about that.
我不能跟他说
Look, I can't tell him
因为我不该知道这件事  但你可以
because I'm not supposed to know, but you can.
我说了他不想听这种话
And I just told you, he doesn't want to hear it.
他的意愿阻止过你开口骂
And when has that ever stopped you before?
-这不一样  -为什么
- This is different. - Why?
因为他为此惭愧
Because he's ashamed.
那他现在就没有正确看待问题
Then he's not thinking right,
他比任何时候都需要你
and he needs your help more than ever.
那我们一起跟他说
Then we're both telling him.
迈克  我不需要那份功劳
Mike, I don't need the credit.
不  这无关功劳  这与我们有关
No, this isn't about credit. This is about us.
他不能指望我会对你有所隐瞒
He can't tell me something and expect me not to tell you.
你想见我
You wanted to see me?
没错  你这一整天去哪儿了
Yes. Where have you been all day?
怎么了  你有事要跟我说吗
Why? Is there something you want to talk about?
对啊  你去哪里了
Yeah, where you've been.
肖恩·卡荷尔昨晚到我门口
Sean Cahill was at my door last night--
哈维  诺玛去世了
Harvey, Norma passed away.
我在帮路易的忙
I've been helping Louis.
诺玛死了
Norma died?
真糟糕
That's terrible.
我还以为你受不了她呢
I thought you couldn't stand her.
我是受不了  但我认为路易爱她...
I couldn't, but I assume Louis loved her, so...
该干什么干什么去吧
Do what you need to do.
因为她是他的秘书  所以他肯定爱她
Because she was his secretary, he must have loved her.
-我不是这意思  -但你就是这么说的
- That's not what I meant. - But it is what you said.
好吧  唐娜  怎么了
Okay, Donna. What's wrong?
那我们先来谈谈这个吧
How about we start with the fact
过去的十个小时里我都在想
that I have been wondering for the last ten hours
你会不会承认昨晚发生的事
if you're going to acknowledge what happened last night.
但你还是这样  所以你肯定不会承认了
But you're you, so of course you're not.
我不会承认什么
I'm not gonna acknowledge it
因为昨晚什么都没发生
because nothing happened last night.
为什么  别说我知道
Why? And don't tell me I know why.
因为你知道那是个错误
Because it would have been a mistake, and you know it.
我知道的是昨晚有事发生了
What I know is something happened,
但在你告诉我你爱我之后就跑掉了
and you ran away, but not before you told me you loved me.
我之所以那么说是为了让你好受点
I did that because I wanted to make you feel better.
你刚才说了什么
What did you just say to me?
我不是这个意思  我不是说...
That's not what I meant. I didn't say that--
因为你可怜我  你说了
Because you pity me? Yeah, you did.
不是  我那么说是因为我爱你
No, I said it because I love you,
我希望你知道
and I wanted you to know it.
怎么爱我了
Love me how?
-为什么非得...  -怎么爱我了
- Why does that have to-- - Love me how?
跟我想的一样
That's what I thought.
你要么无法回答要么不想回答
You either can't answer or you won't,
简直胡扯  因为显然
which is bullshit, because obviously,
你根本不是那么看我的
you don't just look at me this way.
你可以那么看待我
You're capable of looking at me that way,
但你不想让世界崩溃
but you don't want to let those worlds collide
因为你害怕失去一切
because you're afraid to risk anything.
因为我们拥有一切
Because we have everything.
不  哈维  是你拥有一切
No, Harvey. You have everything.
那你想要拥有一切吗
So you're saying you want everything?
我不知道  哈维
I don't know, Harvey,
但我知道  我不需要你的怜悯
but what I do know is I don't want your pity.
你在这里做什么  没人知道我住这里
What are you doing here? Nobody finds out where I live.
我知道
I do.
稍等  我把这个关掉
Hold on a second. Let me turn this off.
你开玩笑吧  你在看《华尔街》
You got to be kidding me. You're watching Wall Street?
《华尔街》为1987年奥利弗·斯通导演的电影
每月一次提醒自己
A monthly ritual to remind myself.
提醒什么
Of what?
戈登.盖可有多娘炮
Of what a pussy Gordon Gekko is.
戈登·盖可为电影《华尔街》中臭名昭著的金融家
说说你怎么改变主意了吧
Now, you want to tell me what changed your mind?
我认为我还是需要钱
I decided I wanted the money.
你拒绝过我
And you turned me down,
现在你得告诉我为什么需要钱
so now you're gonna tell me why you want the money.
我弟弟需要十五万开餐馆
My brother needs $150,000 for a restaurant.
现在有的谈了
Now we're getting somewhere.
-说吧  -好吧  你想听吗
- Let's have it. - Okay, you want it?
是这样的
Here it is.
这不只是个餐馆  还是个洗心革面的机会
It's not just a restaurant. It's a second chance.
马库斯赌博成瘾
Marcus has a gambling problem,
是我害他染上的
and I gave it to him.
你觉得这是他重新做人的机会
And you think this is his way out?
这确实是
I know it is.
咱俩不怎么对路呀
We're not a good fit,
餐馆经常倒闭
'cause restaurants fail,
一旦他的餐馆倒闭  你就会离开
and when this one does, you'll leave.
所以你还是现在就离开的好
So you might as well leave right now.
不如我们赌一把
Then how about we bet on it?
你要靠赌博
You're gonna gamble on something
帮你弟弟摆脱赌瘾吗
to get your brother out of a gambling problem?
-我又没说我有赌瘾  -说不定你有呢
- I didn't say I had a problem. - I think maybe you do.
如果总赢不输  这就不是问题了
When you always win, it's not a problem.
我觉得我会喜欢你的  伙计
I think I might like you, pal.
路易
Louis.
我收到你的短信  怎么了
I got your message. What's going on?
怎么了  他们想糊弄我
What's going on is, they're trying to screw me,
我要你来唱白脸
and I need you to be bad cop.
什么
What?
您选好了吗  先生
Have you made a decision, sir?
没有  没选好  你个赚死人钱的奸商
No, I haven't made a decision, you shyster dealer of death.
我想我们还需要点时间
Okay, I think maybe we're gonna need another minute.
不  不需要
No, we don't.
我才不需要再选
I don't need another minute to see
这个跟家得宝的水壶似的
that this looks like a pot from Home Depot,
这个像是六号汽车旅馆的台灯
this looks like a lamp from Motel 6,
这个像见鬼的榴弹炮
and this looks like a goddamn howitzer shell.
你真幸运
You are lucky that I don't
我没把这破罐子
take this mockery of a final resting place
买下来塞你屁眼里
and shove it up your ass.
-路易  够了  -不够
- Louis, that's enough. - No, it's not enough.
我为这破事折腾两天了
I've been handling this bullshit for two days
还是为了那个本应该来帮我做事的女人
for a woman who's supposed to be handling things for me.
路易  你发脾气不是因为骨灰瓮
Louis, this isn't about the urn.
少跟我煽情
Oh, please don't give me that touchy-feely shit.
你为什么不给我唱白脸
And why the hell are you not being bad cop?
因为现在需要的不是这个
Because that's not what's needed.
去他的不是这个
Oh, bullshit it's not what's needed.
-路易  -你一点不关心我
- Louis. - You don't care about me.
你从来不关心我
You never cared about me.
你只关心你自己
All you care about is yourself...
还有你那个蠢姐姐  和你的赫梅尔陶俑
and your stupid sister and your Hummel figurines
还有你的《女作家与谋杀案》重播
and your Murder, She Wrote reruns.
路易  我不是诺玛
Louis, I'm not Norma.
她走了
She's gone...
一切会好起来的
and it's gonna be okay.
她就是个母老虎
She was a battle-ax!
可她是我的母老虎
But she was my battle-ax.
我知道
I know.
她不只是让我孤立无援
Oh, she didn't just leave me high and dry.
还永远离开了我
She left me for good.
我好伤心
I'm so sorry.
没事了
It's okay.
怎么两个一起来了
Both of you?
我俩都为你工作
We both work for you.
所以我们一起来跟你说
Which is why we're both here to say
也许是时候换个调查方向
maybe it's time we explore other options.
你在开玩笑吧
You got to be kidding me.
你在这上面花了两天
You spent two days on this,
就打算缴械投降了吗
and you're ready to throw in the towel?
我们花了五天中的两天来调查
We've spent two of our five days on it,
依旧一无所获
and we still don't have a name,
-所以我们觉得是时候考虑...  -什么
- so we think it's time to consider-- - What?
追究傅滋曼
Going after Forstman
十二年前对你做的事
for whatever he did to you 12 years ago.
-你告诉她了  -是的
- You told her? - Yes, I did.
正如我刚才所说  我俩都为你工作
Because like I said, we both work for you.
也就是说我俩都想帮忙
Which means we both want to help.
你们以为过去十几年
You think I haven't wondered how to go after Forstman
我就没想过怎么对付傅滋曼吗
100 times in the last dozen years?
那为什么不动手
Then why don't you?
因为有危险的不只我一个
Because I'm not the only one at risk.
你是说你弟弟
You mean your brother.
对
Yes, I do.
我不会把他牵扯进来
And I'm not gonna bring him into this,
因为他什么都没做错
because he didn't do anything wrong.
哈维  我不是说...
Harvey, I'm not saying--
你没听到吗
Did you hear me?
他不只有我的把柄
He doesn't just have a gun to my head, okay?
还有我弟弟的
He's got one to my brother's.
你告诉过我多少遍
And how many times have you told me
当别人有你的把柄
that when someone has a gun to your head,
就换个方式解决问题
you figure a different way out?
这可是查尔斯·傅滋曼
This is Charles Forstman.
-没别的办法  -哈维  有...
- There is no other way out. - Harvey, there's--
我把活儿派给你了  你去做事就行
I gave you a job to do. Now do your goddamn job.
撞墙了吧
Well, that was a bust.
-总要试试  -是吗
- We had to try. - Did we?
我就说他会生气  他果然生气了
I told you he'd be pissed off, and he was.
你还说他得听听
Yeah, and you also told me he needed to hear things
不想听的事
that he didn't want to hear.
好吧  现在他只听到
Okay, well, now all he heard is,
他自己不光不能信任我  你也不可信任
not only can't he trust me, he can't trust you either.
不是这样  你知道的
That's not what he heard, and you know it.
他听到的是  你是我在这个世界上
What he heard was that you're the closest person
最亲近的人
in the world to me,
我永远不会瞒着你
I am never gonna keep things from you,
为他干活的也不只我一个
and I'm not the only one in his corner.
我是你在这个世界上最亲近的人
I'm the closest person in the world to you.
当然了  你怎么可以...
Of course you are. How can you even--
我不是在质疑这个
I'm not questioning it.
我是你在这个世界上最亲近的人
I'm the closest person in the world to you,
而我不会上你的族谱
and I wouldn't be on your family tree.
-你是说伍德尔  -没错  我是在说伍德尔
- You're talking about Woodall. - Yes, I'm talking about Woodall.
伍德尔结婚了
Woodall's married.
我们查了他的妻子  什么也没发现
We checked his wife. Nothing.
这就是关键  我们没结婚
That's the thing. We're not married.
好吧  我真的不觉得现在是时候提这个
Okay, I really don't think this is the time to bring that up.
我是认真的
I'm being serious.
我们彻查了每个和他有关系的人
We've exhausted every person that's related to him.
也许是时候查查和他没关系的人了
Maybe it's time we found someone who isn't.
-太天才了  -谢谢
- That's genius. - Thank you.
现在我是真不明白为何哈维不尊重你了
Now I really don't understand why Harvey doesn't respect you.
说早了
It's too soon.
这个玩笑开早了
It's too soon for that joke.
早了
Too soon.
我可以随便选吗
I can have any one?
随便选
Take your pick.
没关系  反正你都会输
It doesn't matter, 'cause you're gonna lose.
真是有趣了
That's funny.
我倒觉得我会赢两次呢
I look at it like I'm gonna win twice.
我要开辆很叼的车  狠狠赢你一把
I get to drive a badass car, and I get to kick your ass.
自大  我喜欢
Cocky. I like that.
像你这种人  我很惊讶你居然可以忍受
A guy like you, I'm surprised you could stand working
替卡梅隆·丹尼斯工作
for Cameron Dennis in the first place.
-什么意思  -他不喜欢自大的人
- What do you mean? - He doesn't like cocky.
就拿那谁  什么名字来着...杜彭
Take, for instance, what's-his-name--DuPont?
他是怎么回事  偷税漏税吗
What's he up for? Tax evasion?
-内幕交易  -是的  随便啦
- Insider trading. - Yeah, whatever.
重点是  在你那天立功了之后
The point is, after what you did the other day,
为什么不是你主导那个案子
why aren't you leading that?
因为这是卡梅隆的案子
Because this is Cameron's case.
假如我是他的话  案子就是你的了
If I were him, it'd be yours.
哈维  你是他的明星选手
Harvey, you are his star player,
而他却连场都不让你上
and he's not even putting you in the game.
更重要的是
And on top of that,
他没胆量宣告他到底要不要查杜彭
he didn't have the balls to announce whether he's going after DuPont or not.
你就不操心卡梅隆·丹尼斯了
Don't you worry about Cameron Dennis.
杜彭会罪有应得的
DuPont's gonna get what's coming to him.
我就是想听这句话
That's exactly what I wanted to hear.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
你忠于你的雇主
Well, you're loyal to the guy you work for.
我喜欢
I like that.
所以你刚刚就说他坏话
So you were just talking shit about him
看看我会不会上钩吗
to see if I'd jump on board?
而你没上钩...
And you didn't...
因此我们也没必要赛车了
which is why we don't have to race anymore.
你是说我得到了这份工作吗
You're saying I got the job?
欢迎加入
I'm saying welcome to the team.
这一切都很棒  查尔斯
Well, that's all well and good, Charles,
但我们还是要赛一场
but we're still racing.
当然要赛
We sure as hell are.
只不过需要另寻一个赌注了
We just have to find something else to bet on.
你好啊  肖恩  见到你真高兴
Hey, Sean. Good to see you.
别给我来这套
Don't give me that shit.
你昨天早上在埃里克·伍德尔逛超市时
Did you confront Eric Woodall yesterday morning
去找他了吗
at his supermarket?
我们偶然碰上了
I ran into him by accident.
我喜欢那家超市的农产品
I like the produce there.
我现在没心情开玩笑  哈维
I'm not in the mood, Harvey.
你是接近了证监会调查中的涉案人员
Did you approach the subject of an SEC investigation
并且恐吓他了吗
with the express purpose of intimidating him?
我接近他是为了
I approached him with the express purpose
让他雇我做他的律师
of hiring me as his lawyer.
你为什么要干那种事
Why the hell would you do that?
你应该是来帮我的
You're supposed to be helping me.
假如他愿意承认自己做了什么
And if he's willing to admit what he did,
那就帮到你了
that is helping you.
相反  他声称我派你去那里恐吓他
And instead, he's claiming that I sent you there to intimidate him.
我猜这就是突破的方式
Then I guess that's the way it's breaking.
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
他要么选择买我的帐
He's either gonna buy what I'm selling
要么掩饰自己留下的痕迹
or cover his tracks.
假如他要掩饰痕迹  你得去抓他现行
And if he covers his tracks, you need to be there.
你是请求我跟踪他吗
Are you asking me to follow him?
不  我是要求你要跟踪他
No, I'm telling you to follow him.
我不能那样做  我没有权限
I can't do that. I don't have authorization.
那你还跟踪我
Didn't stop you following me.
够了
Enough.
他要控告我骚扰
He's filing charges of harassment against me.
我们这样做根本没用
We do this, nothing sticks.
那也许我们没办法抓到他了
Then we might not get him,
因为我手上什么也没有
because I have nothing.
让我给你一点额外的动力
Well, let me give you a little extra motivation.
记住  伍德尔知道一切关于路易·利特的
Remember, Woodall knows all about
那点和傅滋曼有关的小罪行
Louis Litt's little Forstman transgression.
所以假如他被证明无罪
So if he gets exonerated,
你觉得他第一个会找谁报仇
who do you think's gonna be the first person he goes after?
所以  与其去新泽西买你的农产品
So, instead of going to Jersey for your produce,
还不如弄点我能用得上的东西
go get me something I can use.
怎么在一个人喝闷酒
You're having a drink by yourself?
发生什么事情了
What's going on?
发生的事情是
What's going on is,
我刚刚让人把杰夫的名字从他门上刮下来了
I just finished having them scrape Jeff's name off his door.
你不说说你为什么在这里吗  哈维
So why don't you tell me why you're here, Harvey?
卡荷尔找不到证据
Cahill's having trouble getting evidence
指控傅滋曼和伍德尔
against Forstman and Woodall.
我知道
I'm aware of that.
那你也应该知道
Then you should also be aware that
假如伍德尔保住了他的工作
if Woodall keeps his job,
就会去找路易的麻烦
he's likely to go after Louis.
我能想明白那点  你也可以
I could've done that math, and so could you,
所以...
so...
我也许可以帮他们抓到傅滋曼...
I might be able to help them get Forstman...
通过别的事情
on something else.
这和他12年前
Does this have something to do
给你那份工作的事有关系吗
with when he offered you that job 12 years ago?
有关
Yes.
我说了那人是个大麻烦
I told you that man was trouble.
我也说了我不会放弃马库斯
And I told you I wouldn't abandon Marcus
而且你看错他了
and you were wrong about him.
所以这事还和马库斯有关
So this has something to do with Marcus.
是的
Yes, it does.
如果你是想让我在
Well, if you are asking me to choose
你弟弟和路易之间做选择  你知道结果
between your brother and Louis, you know who I'm choosing.
我没让你做选择
I'm not asking you to do that.
那你想让我干什么
Then what are you asking?
我想让你帮我整理思路
I want your help to get my mind right.
问题在于  哈维
Here's the thing, Harvey.
杰夫走了
Jeff's gone,
而他离开是我做的选择导致的
and he's gone because of the choices I made.
所以我不知道我能否为你整理思路
So I'm not sure if I can help you get your mind right,
因为眼下
'cause right now...
我的也是一团糟
mine's not right.
失陪一下
Hang on a sec.
你来这儿不只是为了通知我上班时间吧
You didn't come down here just to give me my start date.
我来是为了告诉你
I came down here to tell you
我觉得你很特别
I think you have something special,
我也很愿意让你为我工作
and I'd love nothing more than to have you on my desk,
但我就要辞去检察官的职位了
but I'm leaving the DA's office.
这和那天请你喝酒的那个
Does this have something to do with that Forstman guy
傅滋曼有关吗
buying you a drink the other night?
你不是不认识他吗
I thought you didn't know who he was.
我查了查他的底细
Well, I looked him up
因为我以为以后要为你工作了
because I thought I was gonna be working for you.
而且我告诉你  他很坏
And I'm telling you, he's shady.
就因为他名声不好吗
Because he's got a bad reputation?
我才不在乎他的名声
I don't care what his reputation is.
你还不了解我  我很会看人
You don't know this about me yet, but I know people...
我对他们的了解有时比他们自己还透彻
usually better than they know themselves.
所以我知道你是个好人
And the same way I know you are a good person,
我还可以告诉你那个人可坏到家了
I can tell you that man is rotten to the core.
你只是为了说服我
You're just trying to get me to stay
让你做我的秘书
so you can work at my desk.
听着
Listen to me.
我不在乎你要不要雇我
I don't care whether I work on your desk or not.
为那个人干活绝对是个大错误
You're making a mistake if you take a job with that man.
那恐怕我在犯大错误了
Then I guess I'm making a mistake,
因为我已经接受了他的邀请
because I already did.
认识你很高兴  唐娜
It was nice knowing you, Donna.
所以你最终还是决定留下她了
So you're keeping her here after all.
在你把我弄哭后  我也没办法
Yeah, I couldn't throw her off the roof
把她从屋顶撒下去了
after you got me to cry.
太好了
I'm glad.
唐娜  我都不知道该怎么感谢你
Donna, I can't thank you enough for what you did.
不用客气  路易
Oh, you're welcome, Louis.
事实是  这让我也好了很多
The truth is, I needed this more than you know.
我理解
Well, I get it.
你需要分分神
You needed a distraction
因为刚刚过去的这些麻烦事
after everything you just went through.
是啊  算是吧
Uh, yeah. Something like that.
老实说
Truth is,
我自己也需要分分神
I could use a distraction myself.
还有件事你需要做
Well, there is one thing that you still need to do.
你得开始想着找新秘书了
You need to start thinking about a new secretary.
唐娜  我知道我之前问过你
Donna, I know I've asked you this before,
但现在我们的关系比当时近多了  而且
but we're so much closer now than we were then, and--
路易  我为哈维工作
Louis, I work for Harvey.
你知道我不能当你的秘书
You know I can't be your secretary.
但我们心意相通啊
But we have this bond...
你和我
you and I.
我们都喜欢莎士比亚  喜欢射击俱乐部
Shakespeare, the gun club.
我们一向有共同语言  你自己也知道的
We've always spoken the same language, and you know it.
路易  我不能这么做
Louis, I can't.
我理解
I get it.
我们还是当朋友更好些
We're better as friends.
不如我为诺玛办场小型告别会吧
How about I set up a little farewell for Norma
作为你临时秘书的最后一项工作
as my last official act as your interim secretary?
谢谢你  唐娜
Thank you, Donna.
你确定地址没错吗
Are you sure we've got the right address?
确定
I'm positive.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
有什么能帮您的吗
Can I help you?
我们想找玛丽·安·玛葛拉
Uh, yes, is there a Mary Ann McGrath here?
请问您是哪位
Who can I say is asking?
我们来自皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
We're with Pearson Specter Litt.
我们想就一桩调查中的案子和她谈谈
We'd like to speak with her in regards to an ongoing case.
我想这恐怕不行
I'm afraid that won't be possible.
你刚说她在的  我不明白
You just said she was here. I don't understand--
玛丽·安得了老年痴呆症
Mary Ann has advanced Alzheimer's.
但她才55岁
But she's 55.
是早发性的  而且她的症状尤其严重
It's early onset, and hers is particularly aggressive.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
能告诉我们她患病多久了吗
Can I ask how long she's been a patient?
我们不能透露病人信息
We're not supposed to disclose any--
拜托  这事很重要
Please. It's really important.
她是一年半左右前被转来这里的
She was moved her about a year and a half ago.
那之前呢
And before that?
我不太清楚
I don't really know,
但我想之前她受到的治疗不怎么好
but I don't think she was getting the best care.
谢谢
Thank you.
我妈妈才55岁
My mother's 55.
如果她能来这里是因为傅滋曼的资助
You know, and if she's only here because Forstman pays for it--
我知道
I know.
哈维要我们找到
Harvey wants us to find
伍德尔亲近的人
the person Woodall's close to.
我们也只能做到这一步
That's all we can do.
我们能做到这一步
Well, "All we can do"
意味着再送她回一个条件很差的医院
is gonna send her back to some horrible facility.
-那也不一定  -肯定的
- We don't exactly know that. - Yes, we do.
瑞秋  这确实很糟糕
Rachel, it's terrible.
我跟你一样不喜欢这样
I don't like it any more than you do,
但这不取决于我们
but it's not up to us.
我知道
I know.
只是这糟透了
It just sucks.
你个该死的骗子
You goddamn liar.
别生气
Oh, don't be mad.
没错  肯奇塔告诉大家我不在家
Yeah, Conchita tells everybody I'm not home.
你知道我在说什么
You know what I'm talking about.
杜彭投资今天跌停了
DuPont Investments dropped through the floor today,
而你抛空了
and you sold short
根据我私下告诉你的信息
based on something that I told you in confidence.
我不记得你告诉过我什么
I don't recall you telling me anything at all.
你个婊子养的
You son of a bitch.
这次交易你赚了1亿多美元
You made over $100 million on that trade.
是啊  没错
Yeah, I did.
欢迎来到现实世界  伙计
Welcome to the real world, pal.
我的现实世界里可不会跟年轻检察官交友
My real world doesn't involve befriending young attorneys
以获得内幕信息
to get inside information.
也许你跟我真的合不来
Maybe you're not the right man for me after all.
你觉得发生了这些事我还想为你工作吗
You think I still want to work for you after this?
你想要赢得竞争和钱
You wanted competition and money.
你赢得了竞争
You got the competition.
这里还有你的钱
Here's your money.
你自己留着那100万吧
You can shove that $1 million up your ass,
因为我不仅不会接受你的工作
because I'm not only not taking your job,
我还要起诉你
I'm gonna prosecute you.
那你在起诉书里也得写上你的名字
Then you might as well add your name to the indictment
既然你已经跟我共享收益
since you've already shared in the profits.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
看看这张支票吧
Take a look at this check.
不是100万
It's not $1 million.
是85万
It's 850,000.
我猜你知道另外15万上哪儿去了
Bet you can guess where the other $150,000 went.
你干了什么
What did you do?
你知道我干了什么
You know what I did.
马库斯跟这事毫无关系
Marcus had nothing to do with this.
如果你马上答应了  他确实是没关系
He wouldn't have had you said yes right away.
但你没有
But you didn't.
我们会把钱还给你
We're giving you the money back.
你会伤透了他的心的
You're gonna break his little heart.
他以为这钱是你给的
He thinks that money came from you.
你从赌徒手里把钱抢走
And you snatch cash out of an addicted gambler's hands,
夺走他的梦想
take away his dream,
那这个故事只有一个结局
only one way that story ends.
所以你要么继续生气
So you can either pout about it...
要么接受现实  然后向大家证明
or you can embrace it and prove to everyone I was right
我说你有特别之处  是对的
when I said I saw something special in you.
风水轮流转  查尔斯
Someday the shoe's gonna be on the other foot, Charles.
我见过的每个输家都这么说
Words spoken by every loser I've ever met.
回见  伙计
See you around, pal.
是伍德尔的发妻
It's Woodall's first wife.
她名叫玛丽·安  他们一起长大
Her name's Mary Ann. They grew up together.
21岁时结婚
They got married when they were 21
6个月后离婚
and had it annulled six months later.
那笔钱是做什么用的
And what's the money for?
-她得了老年痴呆症  -别告诉我
- She has Alzheimer's. - Don't tell me.
他让她住进高级疗养院
He moved her to a high-end facility
支付24小时监护费
and pays for round-the-clock care.
问题是  我们给处理账单的
And the problem is, we called the company
公司打了电话  然后
that handles the billing, and--
全用现金支付
And everything's in cash up front,
可能还预支了五年的费用
probably paid five years in advance.
但玛丽·安没法告诉你  因为她不能说话
And Mary Ann couldn't tell you because she doesn't speak.
所以我们根本没有证据
Which mean we don't have any proof.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我去找证据
I'm gonna go get us some proof.
这是你发现的吗
You did this?
迈克和我一起
Mike and I both did.
那他为什么没来
Then why isn't he here?
你知道原因
You know why.
因为功劳大半在你
Because it was more you than him.
干得不错  瑞秋
You did a good job, Rachel.
购物  租碟
Shopping, renting videos.
你一定快被逼疯了吧
You must be going stir-crazy.
没关系
That's all right.
我停职期快满了
My suspension is about to expire.
对啊  换作是我可不敢指望
Yeah, I wouldn't count on it.
我们发现玛丽·安了
We found Mary Ann.
我听说她在新疗养院过得不错
I'm told she's doing well at the new facility--
傅滋曼的公司付钱的那家
you know, the one Forstman's paying for.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
我不是来利用你的悲剧  埃里克
I'm not here to exploit your tragedy, Eric.
我是来告诉你  一切都结束了
I'm here to tell you it's over.
如果真的结束了
Well, if this were over,
你现在会跟跟肖恩·卡荷尔在一起
you'd be with Sean Cahill right now,
所以你是来找我达成协议的
which means you're still looking for me to cut a deal.
我是来找你对付傅滋曼的
I'm looking for you to turn on Forstman.
你三天内两次来找我
You accost me for the second time in three days
还搬出了玛丽·安的名字
and throw Mary Ann's name around
作为你的谈判筹码
like a bargaining chip,
你觉得我会帮你吗
and you think I'm gonna help you?
去死吧
Drop dead.
埃里克  拜托了
Eric, please.
我知道要找一个你在乎的人
The reason I knew to look for someone that you cared about
是因为傅滋曼也那样对过我
was that Forstman did the same thing to me.
他发现你的弱点  然后利用弱点
He finds your weakness and presses down
直到你不再有对抗他的意志
until you don't have the will to stand up to him.
你的弱点是得了老年痴呆症的前妻
With you, it was an ex-wife with Alzheimer's.
而我
With me...
就是有赌瘾的弟弟
it was a little brother addicted to gambling.
我才不管
I don't care.
你没证据
You don't have proof,
再过一天你也找不到
and you're not gonna get it in the next 24 hours.
你说得对  我没有
You're right. I don't.
可问题是
But here's the thing.
卡荷尔可能有时间期限  但我没有
Cahill may have a deadline, but I don't,
我也不在乎要花多长时间
and I don't care how long it takes,
要是你不去对付傅滋曼的话
because I'm gonna find that proof
我一定会对那份证据追查到底
if you don't turn on Forstman.
很多人不知道这事
A lot of you don't know this,
但实际上  我恨死诺玛了
but the truth is, I hated Norma.
我讨厌她的木屐
I hated her clogs,
她的胡子
her mustache,
又丑又傻的应季毛衣
her stupid seasonal sweaters.
但我最讨厌的是
But the thing I hated most about her
她老是喜欢炫耀
was her favorite story
1975年阿贝·维高达[美国演员]向她求过婚
about how Abe Vigoda asked her to marry him in 1975.
大家都懂的
I mean, we get it.
你曾美丽又性感
You were hot.
拒绝他的求婚
You turned him down,
是你这辈子最后悔的事
and it was the biggest regret of your life.
就像你说过的所有事一样
And like everything you ever said,
当时令我难以忍受
I couldn't stand it at the time.
但现在你不在了
But now that you're gone,
我终于明白你话里的含义
I understand what you meant.
莫错过光阴
Don't let the moment pass.
莫在未表白心意前
Don't let the people you love walk by you
就放手爱人  任其离开
without letting them know how you feel about them,
因为放手一瞬  后悔一生
because life slips by, and then it's over.
现在我要告诉你  你对我来说有多重要
And I'm not gonna let another minute pass me by
不会再让一分一秒从身边溜走
without letting you know how much you mean to me.
诺玛  我爱你
I love you, Norma.
谢谢  路易
Thank you, Louis.
致辞很感人
That was a lovely ceremony.
说的真好  路易
That was beautiful, Louis.
没有你我做不到的
I couldn't have done it without you.
-你就别谦虚了  -本来就是
- Oh, that's not true. - Yeah, it is.
没有你点醒我  我都不知道自己的感受
I couldn't even see how I felt without you showing me.
事实是  唐娜
And the truth is, Donna,
你比我自己还要了解我
you know me better than I know myself.
就像我之前说的  哈维根本不知道
Like I said, Harvey has no idea
拥有你是多幸运的一件事
how lucky he is to have you.
是在找我可能给埃里克·伍德尔的那笔钱吗
Looking for the money I supposedly gave Eric Woodall?
你是来直接认罪  帮我省事的吗
You want to save me the trouble and just admit what you did?
不是  要是那样还有什么意思
No, where would be the fun in that?
好  你继续玩吧
Fine. Keep playing your games,
但这一次  你必败无疑
but this time, you're gonna lose.
为什么  你以为你说服了伍德尔供出我吗
Why, because you think you convinced Woodall to give me up?
没错  他来找我了
Yeah, he came to see me.
说你想让他出卖我
Said you tried to get him to turn me in.
我说的是  你是个傲慢的混蛋
What I said was, you're an arrogant bastard
整天盘算着怎么利用别人
who's spent his life manipulating people.
那你就是个只关心输赢的废柴
And you're the loser who only cares about competition.
赢不了我  怪我咯
Not my fault you can't beat me.
这次我可以
I can this time.
我不觉得  伙计  因为...
Oh, I don't think so, pal, because...
他卖我  我就卖你
he turns on me, I turn on you.
如果你说的是十二年前的那件事  容我提醒下
If you're talking about 12 years ago, let me remind you.
我们都参与其中了
We were both part of that deal.
是的
Yes, we were.
我们三个都参与了  我  你  和你弟弟
All three of us were-- you, me, and your brother.
你别把我弟弟搅和进来
You leave my brother out of this.
想都别想
Not a chance.
要是你非不放过伍德尔这事
And you don't leave this Woodall thing alone,
那么我完蛋的那天
by the time I'm done,
所有人都会知道十二年前
all anybody will know about 12 years ago
是你给了条建议
is you gave me a tip
确保你的弟弟能从中获利
and made sure your little brother profited from it.
我屁都没有给过你
I didn't give you shit.
你骗我给你透内部消息
You tricked me into giving you inside information
然后给马库斯一笔
and then blackmailed me
他自己都不知道是赃款的钱来勒索我
by giving Marcus money he didn't even know was dirty.
那或许是真相
That may be the truth,
但他们不会从我这里听到
but they're never gonna hear it from me.
恐怕他们刚刚就听到了
I'm afraid they just did.
你好啊  查尔斯
Hi, Charles.
我是肖恩·卡荷尔  很高兴见到你
Sean Cahill. Nice to meet you.
你他妈是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是证监会里还没被你收买的人
I'm the guy from the SEC that isn't in your pocket.
我让肖恩去跟踪伍德尔
I asked Sean to follow Woodall.
做不到  我没有权限
Couldn't. No authorization.
但是要获得跟踪你的授权
But I had no problem getting authorization
就没什么难度
to follow you.
所以我才知道什么时候该把它打开
Which is how I knew when to turn this on.
你竟然戴了窃听器
You're wearing a goddamn wire?
某人还说自己最爱的电影是《华尔街》呢
For someone whose favorite movie is Wall Street,
这都没发现  真是丢人啊
that's got to be pretty embarrassing.
你个混蛋
Son of a bitch.
查尔斯  十二年前你或许赢了我
You may have gotten the better of me 12 years ago, Charles,
但这次  你没有
but this time, you didn't.
记住这种感觉  因为我知道我会的
So remember what it feels like, because I know I will.
哈维  这事没完
Harvey, this isn't over.
我见过的每个输家都这么说
Words spoken by every loser I've ever met.
回见  伙计
See you around, pal.
二换二
Two for two.
他没碰我的球
He didn't touch my balls.
黑咖  两块方糖  再加一点香草
Black, two sugars, splash of vanilla.
你怎么知道我喝咖啡的习惯
How do you know that's how I take my coffee?
跟知道你不会接受那份工作同样的渠道
The same way I know you're not taking that job.
你知道我不会接是因为我今天来上班了
You know I'm not taking that job because I came into work today.
不  斯佩克特先生
No, Mr. Specter.
那天晚上你从我身边走开的时候
I knew you weren't taking that job
我就知道你不会接那份工作
the second you walked away from me the other night.
早跟你说过我对别人的了解比他们自己还透彻
I told you I know people better than they know themselves.
那蒂娜怎么办
Well, what did you do with Tina?
我让贝莎重新分配了
Oh, I had Big Bertha reassign her.
-分给谁了  -你真的关心吗
- To who? - Do you really care?
-毫不关心  -很好
- Not a bit. - Good.
条件是这样
Here's the deal.
我可以为你挡子弹
I will take a bullet for you.
当然不是在说真的子弹
And I don't mean that literally.
但是你要为我做的是
But what you do for me is,
我需要什么的时候  你也要给我
when I need something, you give it to me.
我们的合作是互相的
It's not just a one-way street.
此外你还会真正做秘书的工作吗
Will you also do some actual secretarial work?
看我是怎么安排你的日程表的  牛人
Take a look at what I did with your calendar there, hotshot.
老天啊
Holy shit.
你什么时候做好的
When'd you get that done?
我说过我不是一般的秘书
I told you I'm not like every other secretary.
我可是唐娜
I'm Donna.
那我们开始工作吧
Then let's get to work.
不过顺便说一句  我喝咖啡不加香草
But for the record, I don't take vanilla with my coffee.
你尝过以后就会加了
You will after you taste that.
天呐  真好喝
Oh, my God, this is awesome.
这些人什么时候才会明白
When will they learn?
正是时候
Perfect timing.
而我们要庆祝什么
And what are we celebrating?
我们的胜利
Our win.
"我们的胜利"
"Our win."
-我喜欢这说法  -我也喜欢
- I like the sound of that. - Me too.
你去哪了
Where were you?
我一会再说
I'll get into that in a minute.
我想先和你谈谈
I want to talk to you for a second.
怎么了
What is it?
瑞秋  你知道我告诉过你我爱你
Rachel, you know I told you I loved you
第一次见面我就说过
from the second I met you.
你爱我的铅笔裙
Well, you loved my pencil skirt.
我爱你的面容
I loved your face.
你是我见过的最出色的女人
You're the most amazing woman I have ever met,
你不止美貌
and you're not just beautiful,
而且还甜美  善良  关心人
but you're sweet and caring and kind
而且聪明坚强
and brilliant and tenacious.
迈克  你...
Mike, are--
你是在做我认为你在做的那件事吗
are you doing what I think you're doing?
我今天给你父亲打过电话了
I called your father today.
然后我又把奶奶的戒指送去清洗干净了
And then I went to get Grammy's ring cleaned.
天...
Oh, my--
我不想花四十年时间
I don't want to go 40 years
后悔自己为什么没早一天这样做
wondering why I didn't do this one day sooner.
瑞秋·伊丽莎白·赞恩
Rachel Elizabeth Zane...
我爱你
I love you...
永生永世
and I always will.
你是我生命的全部
You're my whole life.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
愿意
Yes.
-愿意吗  -愿意
- Yes? - Yes.
-好  -来
- All right, - Here...
天呐
Oh, my God.
太漂亮了
It's beautiful.
她一直戴了近六十年
She wore it every day for almost 60 years.
我也会的
So will I.
你好啊  蠢货
What's up, dickhead?
你好啊  笨蛋
What's up, loser?
哈维  听到你的声音真好
Hey, Harvey. Good to hear from you.
怎么了  一切都还好吗
What's going on? Everything okay?
没事  一切都很好
Yeah, everything's okay.
我只是有段时间没和你说话了
I just haven't talked to you in a while
想看看你怎么样
and wanted to see how you were doing.
我很好  凯蒂也很好
I'm great. Katie's good.
孩子们都很好  一切都好
The kids are good. Everything's good.
太棒了
Great.
我就想听到这个
That's exactly what I wanted to hear.
你确定没有别的事吗
You sure there's nothing going on?
没有
Nothing.
就像我刚才说的  我有段时间没跟你说话了
Like I said, I just haven't talked to you in a while,
我想你了
and I miss you.
我也想你  哈维  但除非你还有别的事
I miss you too, Harvey, but unless you got something else,
我得挂了
I've got to go.
我在给孩子们洗澡呢
The kids are in the bath.
没别的事了
Nothing else.
爱你  哈维
Love you, Harvey.
我也爱你
I love you too.
听我说  我考虑过你说的话了
Listen, I was thinking about what you said,
关于我同情你
about me pitying you.
我不是同情你
And I don't.
绝对不是那回事
Nothing could be further from the truth.
我认为你是我认识的最出色的女人之一
I think you're one of the most amazing women I've ever met,
而仅仅因为我不...
and just because I don't--
-我要离开你了  哈维  -什么
- I'm leaving you, Harvey. - What?
我不想再为你工作了
This isn't working for me anymore.
唐娜  我明白你的感受
Donna, I know how you're feeling,
但你刚经历过太多大事
but you just went through something huge,
受审什么的
with being on trial, and, uh...
你需要过些时间再说
you need to give it time.
不能就这样辞职
You can't just quit.
我不是要辞职
I'm not quitting.
我要去为路易工作
I'm going to work for Louis.
唐娜
Donna.
唐娜  拜托
Donna, please.
我爱你  哈维
I love you, Harvey.